Guide to the International Brotherhood of Teamsters Organizing Department Records, 1954-2003 IBT0065
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
IBT Organizing Department Records
1954-2003
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
International Brotherhood of Teamsters
IBT0065
1 Cubic Feet Organizing manuals and workbooks
This collection consists of Teamsters and Meat Cutters Joint Organizing Committee records, and general organizing materials, manuals and tools.
Scope and Contents
This collection houses the minutes, presentations, manuals, workbooks, and correspondence of the IBT Organizing Department. Materials are dated from 1954 to 2003.
Biographical / Historical
The IBT Organizing Department was established in 1974. Prior to 1974 organzing was carried out by general organizers located within the area conferences. In January 1984 the Organizing Department held first National Organizing Conference.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research use.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
This materials was transferred from the IBT in 2015.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged by document type.
General
Labor unions; Labor unions -- United States -- History -- 20th century
- Teamsters and Butchers Joint Organizing Committee Records-Einer O. Mohn, 1954-1955 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Teamsters-Machinists Proposal-Joint Organizing Campaign Records & Correspondence, 1955-1956 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Teamsters and Butchers Joint Organizing Committee Records-Einer O. Mohn-Vol.4 [Part 1], 1956 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Teamsters and Butchers Joint Organizing Committee Records-Einer O. Mohn-Vol.4 [Part 2], 1956 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Teamsters and Butchers Joint Organizing Committee Records-Einer O. Mohn-Vol.4 [Part 3], 1956 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- The Teamsters Slide Show-Talking Points & Text Slides, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Teamsters Organizing Toolkit, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Eastern Conference of Teamsters Manual for Union Organizers Revised, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Eastern Conference of Teamsters Manual for Union Organizers, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Teamsters Organizing Manual, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Organizing in the 80's Eastern Conference of Teamsters Manual for Union Organizers, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- "What is the Teamsters Union" Booklet, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Overnight Transportation Organizing Handbook, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Organizing Department Leaflets, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Steward's Manual, Undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
- How to Write a Union Flyer guide, Undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Legal Organizing Manual, Undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Organizing Department Brochures and Pamphlets, Undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Summary of the IBT Organizing Model, Undated; IBT0065 (Box Shared Box 36, Folder 23)